Erik di Biase

Address - Flat 6, Hanbury House, Hanbury Street, E1 5JD, London, UK

Email - oberonx10@gmail.com

Portfolio - http://www.erikdibiase.com

Phone - 07504 506395

Personal Summary

As a newly graduated game developer, my experience comes mostly from my previous studies as a game programmer. While pursuing my degree I had the opportunity to take on a variety of roles and tasks ranging from designing game mechanics and their implementation, to creating entire games, demos or gameplay tools. Due to the nature of my degree I acquired a solid knowledge of languages such as JavaScript, C, C++, C# as well as experience in utilizing different graphic APIs like OpenGL and DirectX. Whilst being enrolled I also experienced the difficulties of working as a team, creating games in collaboration with graphic and sound artists using Unreal or Unity. I'm now focusing on the use of virtual technology, and their implementation in my previous projects.

Qualifications

2015 – 2018 BSc (Hons) Computer Games Programming 1st

London Metropolitan University

Course modules:

Game Design, Digital Toy Design, Graphic & Imaging, Portfolio, Hardware Architecture, C++ Programming, C++ Programming for Games, Artificial Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence for Games, Prototype Development.

University Projects

Across the entirety of the course length, I developed a considerable number of projects, some as part of a team of students sharing my same module, some personally handling every development task.

Planetary Exploration Nanobot 15 (Unreal/C++) Gameplay & Tools Programmer (Team Project)

Trailer at: https://youtu.be/bKYiVenPM0
Source code at: https://github.com/6Axel9/Protodev

- Inventory handling
- Weapon shooting system
- Cinematics and Animation state machines
- VR support for directional movements
- Xbox One controller support
- Player blueprint and movements
- Pickup mechanic and blueprints
- Item spawning
- Level lighting
- GUI layout

Floor is Icy-Lava (Unity/C#) Game Developer

Source code and Unity scene at: https://github.com/6Axel9/Floor-is-Icy-Lava

- Procedural level generation
- Player inputs and controls
- AI finite state machine
- AI jumping and steering behaviours
- GUI layout and menus

Procedural Environment Generation (OpenGL/C++) Demos Developer

Compliable Source code at: https://github.com/6Axel9/RedaxeGL

- Procedural terrain generation
- Ambient, diffuse and specular lighting
- Light and Normal mapping
- Terrain multi-texturing
- Finite state machine
- Scripted assets loader
- Water shading

T-Wrecks (DirectX/C++) **Gameplay & Tools Programmer** (Team Project)

Source code at: https://github.com/6Axel9/t-wrecks

- Destructible animated objects
- Player animations, inputs and controls
- Store & load assets through binary files
- Grid based collision system
- Game states and menus

Iso Snake (HTML/JavaScript) **Game Developer**

Playable game at: http://www.erikdibiase.com/isosnake

- 3D Grid environment creation
- Player inputs and controls
- Snake design, movements and features
- Score based ending screen

Motor Murder (ToncLib/C) Game Developer

Source code, emulator and rom at: https://github.com/6Axel9/motormurder

- 2D Scrolling level design
- Player inputs and controls
- Weapon shooting system
- Pickups powers and timeout
- Pixel art and GUI layout
- Explosion animations

Employment History

Objective-Z – London

Gameplay Programmer Intern (June 2017 – September 2017)

SRPG – (name subject to changes)

My role in this Unity based project consisted in designing new innovative game mechanics, to be implemented in the game, my work had to be first approved by providing the relative pitch documentation to my team leader then followed by a presentation to the other members. I'd then proceed scripting the mechanic on my own, with the constant feedback of my team leader.

London Metropolitan University – London

PASS Scheme Student (October 2016 – May 2018)

As a PASS Student, my role focused on providing to first year students studying my same course subject with guidance, help through which they could develop and improve, but for me was also an outstanding opportunity to find different ways, methods to perform tasks, game ideas or even just to meet promising students with which I might be able to work with in the future.